Guide to the Eliasaf Robinson Tel Aviv Collection M1522
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Eliasaf Robinson Tel Aviv collection
circa 1909-1975
M1522
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
34.5 Linear feet
An eclectic mix of materials relating to the history of Tel Aviv. Included are census materials, advertisements from the 1920s and 1930s, maps and completion certificates for buildings constructed between 1935-1948, postcards, photographs, municipal documents, land deeds, visa and employment certification requests, flyers and publicity for cultural events, movie handbills before 1948, and business ads.
23 manuscript boxes, 27 map folders
Robinson, Eliasaf
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Purchased and gift, 2005, 2006, 2008, and 2009. Acquired in December 2005 from Eliasaf Robinson, of Tel Aviv, Israel, with support from Koret Foundation Funds and the Jewish Community Endowment Fund of San Francisco, the Peninsula, Marin and Sonoma Counties. Accession numbers 2006-083, 2006-085, 2008-015, 2008-023, 2008-056, 2009-089, and 2009-090.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Digital Collection and Virtual Exhibit available online at http://lib.stanford.edu/telaviv
As of May 18, 2009, the digitized collection includes over one thousand photographs and postcards, three hundred printed volumes, two hundred large format materials (posters, maps and sewer diagrams) and six linear feet of archival materials.
The collection's curator has selected over 750 digitized images and books to be cataloged and added to Stanford's online Image Gallery. This portion of the collection is searchable by title, subject, and description. Books can be read online and images can be viewed in close-up detail.
Biography / Administrative History
Eliasaf Robinson, a native of the city of Tel Aviv, began to gather the materials relating to Tel Aviv in the 1960s, when he was still a teenager. He belongs to the fourth generation in a family dynasty of booksellers and is the most prominent antiquarian book dealer in Israel. The Jewish settlement that became the city of Tel Aviv was established in 1909. Almost everything in this collection dates from before 1948, the year that the State of Israel proclaimed its independence. The collection documents a vast range of private and public activity in Tel Aviv during its first four decades. Above all, the materials in the collection demonstrate the effectiveness of one of the twentieth century?s boldest and most effective acts of social engineering: the revival and enforced use of the Hebrew language. The modern, largely secular, urban Hebrew culture that emerged there during the 1920s and 1930s is the basis of the Israeli culture of today. The photographs, postcards, maps, architectural plans, and construction permits in this collection also document the growth of the "White City" of Tel Aviv, which in March 2003 UNESCO proclaimed a World Heritage Centre. This recognition was based on the city's "synthesis of outstanding significance of the various trends of the Modern Movement in architecture and town planning in the early part of the 20th century."
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection includes census materials, advertisements from the 1920s and 1930s, maps, blueprints and completion certificates for buildings constructed between 1935-1948, postcards, photographs, municipal documents, visa and employment certification requests, land deeds, and publicity for cultural events, including over two hundred movie posters from before 1948. Note: Approximately 500 book and serial titles that are part of the collection are cataloged separately, and are not described in this finding aid.
Arrangement
Series I, Commercial, consists of seven subseries: Subseries A, Advertisements and promotional materials; Subseries B, Banking and finance; Subseries C, Business cards; Subseries D, Business correspondence; Subseries E, Construction and housing; Subseries F, Litvinsky Bros.; Subseries G, Yehoshua Gordon. Series II, Culture, consists of twelve subseries: Subseries A, Cinema; Subseries B, Habimah; Subseries C, Miscellaneous; Subseries D, Ohel Theater; Subseries E, Palestine Opera and Israel Opera; Subseries F, Palestine Orchestra; Subseries G, Palestine Philharmonic Orchestra; Subseries H, Purim; Subseries I, Sheet music; Subseries J, Sport; Subseries K, Tel Aviv Museum; Subseries L, Writing, unpublished. Series III, Maps, consists of three subseries: Subseries A, Tel-Aviv Yafo, published; Subseries B, Tel-Aviv Yafo, unpublished; Subseries C, Other areas.
Series IV, Noncommercial institutions, consists of eleven subseries: Subseries A, Associations, cooperative societies, and committees; Subseries B, Charities; Subseries C, Other cities; Subseries D, Education; Subseries E, Electric Company; Subseries F, Government of Palestine and Israel; Subseries G, Jewish Agency; Subseries H, Legal documents; Subseries I, Medical; Subseries J, Miscellaneous correspondence, etc.; Subseries K, Political activity.
Series V, Photographs, consists of six subseries: Subseries A, Albums, etc.; Subseries B, Buildings, etc.; Subseries C, Commercial; Subseries D, People; Subseries E, Postcards; Subseries F, Published photos.
Series VI, Tel Aviv Municipality, consists of twelve subseries: Subseries A, Administrative documents; Subseries B, Ephemera; Subseries C, Civil Guard (Mishmar ezrahi) and military; Subseries D, Memorabilia; Subseries E, Letters: incoming; Subseries F, Letters: outgoing; Subseries G, Hawker licensing; Subseries H, Meeting minutes; Subseries I, Sewer Department; Subseries J, Street census; Subseries K, Technical Department; Subseries L, Transportation.
Series VII, Clippings, etc.
Adloyada (Festival); Bet ha-keneset ha-gadol (Tel Aviv, Israel); Dizengoff, Meir, 1861-1936; Architecture--Israel--Tel Aviv--20th century.; Children--Israel--Tel Aviv--Pictorial works.; City planning--Israel--Tel Aviv.; Commercial photography--Israel--Tel Aviv.; Fasts and feasts--Judaism.; Holidays--Israel--Tel Aviv.; Immigrants--Palestine--History--20th century.; Industries--Israel--Tel Aviv.; Jaffa (Tel Aviv, Israel) -- History -- 20th century.; Nemal Tel-Aviv (Israel); Postcards.; Posters.; Purim.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--Commerce.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--Economic conditions.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--History.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--Maps.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--Politics and government.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--Population--Pictorial works.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--Population.
- Series I. Commercial
  - Subseries A. Advertisements and promotional materials
    - Handbills, promotional correspondence, postcards, pamphlets, and prospectuses (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Kaiser-Frazer of Israel Ltd.: exhibition news = Ḳaizer-Fraizer le-Yiśra‛el be-‘e. m.: ḥadashot ha-ta‘arukhah., 1953-09-22; 1.0 item(s) (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Automobile industry and trade--Israel; Promotional materials
    - Handbills, promotional correspondence, postcards, pamphlets, and prospectuses (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Handbills, promotional correspondence, postcards, pamphlets, and prospectuses (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Medicines of repute = Same ha-refu’ah ba‘ale ‘erekh gadol., 1900-1920; 1.0 volume(s); Burroughs Welcome and Company. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Burroughs Welcome and Company.; Drugs; Sales catalogs.
    - Handbills, promotional correspondence, postcards, pamphlets, and prospectuses (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Palmad-- ḥevrah E.Y. li-refu’ot be-‘e.m.T.A., 1920-1940; 1 manufacturer's catalog.; Palmad (Pharmaceutical Company: Palestine) (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Palmad (Pharmaceutical Company: Palestine); Manufacturers' catalogs; Pharmaceutical industry; Pharmaceutical industry--Palestine
    - Handbills, promotional correspondence, postcards, pamphlets, and prospectuses (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Luaḥ 5623 [1922/1923]., 1.0 item(s) (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Calendar, Jewish; Calendars.; Religious calendars
      - "Bul-hanaḥah": album le-osef bulim / me-et Miśrad "Ankona", Tel-Aviv., 1900-1950; 1.0 volume(s); Ankona. (Firm: Tel Aviv, Israel) (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Albums.; Trading-stamps--Israel
      - Album of vinegar labels from Mandate Palestine., 1900-1950; 1.0 volume(s) (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Advertising.; Labels; Vinegar industry--Palestine.
  - Poster-sized sales promotions (Map-folder 7)
  - Oversized promotional materials (Flat-box 22, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B. Banking and finance
    - Accounts, checks, receipts, stock certificates (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Accounts, checks, receipts, stock certificates (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C. Business cards
    - Business cards (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Business cards (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries D. Business correspondence
    - Business correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Business correspondence (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Subseries E. Construction and housing
    - Blueprints, including residential as well as plans for the Labor Bureau building at Yavneh 12 in Tel Aviv, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Construction completion certificates (bound), 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Documents, including printed and handwritten lists of purchasers of lots in Tel Aviv (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Documents, including printed and handwritten lists of purchasers of lots in Tel Aviv (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Two brass address plates from a local metal casting factory, “W-L-M Tel-Aviv” and “Aba Neeman, Yafo Tel-Aviv,” undated. (Flat-box 17)
    - Ramat Tikvah sales contract, 1935; Palestine Government Certificate of Registration, Kerem Hatemanim, 1924; Ramat Nof Bet, sales contract (blank), 1930s; Jaffa municipality building permit applications, ca. 1911; blueprints and drawings, 1930s and 1940., 1924-1940 (Flat-box 22, Folder 7)
    - Newsletter of "Ḥevrat "Geʾulah," Tel-Aviv, Erets-Yiśraʾel., 1924; 1.0 item(s); Ge’ulah (Firm: Tel Aviv, Israel) (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Land settlement--Israel--Tel Aviv; Land tenure--Israel--Tel Aviv; Neighborhood planning--Israel--Tel Aviv; Promotional materials
    - ha-Peles be-‘e. m., Maḥlaḳat hakhsharah u-vinyan = "Hapeless" Ltd., Bau-u hedling Abteilung., 1930-1950; 1.0 item(s); Peles (Firm: Palestine) (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Construction industry--Israel--Tel Aviv; Neighborhood planning--Israel--Tel Aviv; Promotional materials
  - Subseries F. Litvinsky Bros.
    - Materials in Ottoman Turkish and ticket to H.N. Bialik funeral (July 16, 1934), etc. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Subseries G. Yehoshua Gordon
    - Personal and business correspondence, 1915-1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - ha-Sheḩorim ṿeha-lavanim., 1957-09-22; 1.0 volume(s); Teveth, Shabtai, 1925- (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Israel--Ethnic relations; Israel--Social conditions--20th century; Pamphlets; Sephardim--Israel--Social conditions
    - Luaḥ 695 (1934/1935): havu ḳarḳa‘ le-visus ha-‘liyah. [Issued by Ḳeren Ḳayemet le-Yiśra’el, Yerushalayaim]., 1.0 item(s); Jewish National Fund. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Taḳanot Banḳ le-ḳrediṭ gomlin: agudah hadadit be-‘eravon mugbal, Tel-Aviv. 686., 1925-1926; 1.0 volume(s); Banḳ le-ḳrediṭ gomlin (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Banḳ le-ḳrediṭ gomlin; Banks and banking--Israel--Tel Aviv; Pamphlets; Tel Aviv (Israel)--Commerce.
  - Subseries H. Real estate contracts
    - Contracts (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series II. Culture
  - Subseries A. Cinema
    - Handbills, tickets, programs, and correspondence, 1920s-1930s (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Ḳolno‘a ‘Eden, toknnit 1934/35 = Cinema Eden, programme; western electric sound system., 1934-1935; 1.0 item(s)
        Motion pictures--Israel--Tel Aviv; Programs
      - Migdalor: tokhnit = Migdalor Programme., 1939-1939; 1.0 item(s); Migdalor. (Theater: Tel Aviv, Israel)
    - Movie posters: 1926, 1930 (Map-folder 1)
      - Paris La Nuit, 1926-06-16; 1.0 item(s); Itin & Shoshany.
        Film posters.; Jaffa (Tel Aviv, Israel) -- History -- 20th century.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--History.
      - La Belle Tenebreuse, 1930-11-22; 1.0 item(s); Cinema Eden.; Garbo, Greta, 1905-1990
      - The Singing Fool, 1930-05-19; 1.0 item(s); Cinema Eden.; Itin & Shoshany.
      - Symphonie Nuptiale, 1930-11-14; 1.0 item(s); S. Shoshany
        Cinema Eden.; Film posters.; Jaffa (Tel Aviv, Israel) -- History -- 20th century.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--History.
      - The Divine Lady, 1930-11-21; 1.0 item(s)
        Cinema Ophir.; Film posters.; Jaffa (Tel Aviv, Israel) -- History -- 20th century.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--History.
      - King of Jazz, 1930-11-14; 1.0 item(s)
      - Wild Heart (When love comes along), 1930-09-19; 1.0 item(s)
        Talkies Opera Mograbi.; Film posters.; Jaffa (Tel Aviv, Israel) -- History -- 20th century.; Tel Aviv (Israel)--History.
      - Terre De Volupte, 1929-08-29; 1.0 item(s)
    - Movie posters: 1930 (Map-folder 2)
    - Movie posters: 1930 (Map-folder 3)
    - Movie posters: 1931 (Map-folder 4)
    - Movie posters: 1931, 1932, and 1933, 1931-1933 (Map-folder 5)
    - Movie posters: 1934, 1935, 1936, and undated, 1934-1936 (Map-folder 6)
    - Movie posters: 1929 (Map-folder 8)
    - Movie posters: 1929 (Map-folder 9)
    - Movie posters: 1930 (Map-folder 10)
    - Movie posters: 1930 (Map-folder 11)
    - Movie posters: 1936 and undated (Map-folder 12)
  - Subseries B. Habimah Theater
    - Correspondence 1920s-1950s, etc. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Habimah: maḥazor ha-hatsagot le-minuiyim li-shenat 707-708 (1947). Siv̤an-Ṭevet, Yuni-Detsember., 1947-1948; Digtial images 00017085_0011 - 00017085_0013; 1.0 volume(s); Habimah. (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Theater programs.; Theater--Israel--Tel Aviv
  - Subseries C. Culture, misc.
    - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Gan zo’ologi u-Muze’on le-ṭeva‘ ‘ironiyim le-Tel-Aviv / Agudat yedide ha-Makhon ha-bi’ologi-pedagogi be-Tel-Aviv. 1 pamphlet. 1938-1939. Makhon ha-bi’ologi-pedagogi be-Tel-Aviv.
    - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Palestine Shipping Co.: program of social events and entertainment: Programm der vorgesehenen Unterhaltungen.
      - Haḳafot shel beḥirot: mizmor shir li-khevod ha-Mo‘atsah ha-ḥamishit shel ‘Iriyat Tel-Aviv / me-et Almoni.
    - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Vinyl LP record, "Roni Yedidyah," ca. 1980s; Palestine Theatre Limited, Share Warrant certificate, 1923. (Flat-box 22, Folder 1)
    - Performance posters. (Map-folder 13)
    - Performance posters. (Map-folder 14)
    - Misc. Performances, Posters 1929-1931 (Map-folder 24)
  - Subseries D. Ohel Theater
    - Correspondence and four programs, 1930s and 1940s. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Subseries E. Palestine Opera and Israel Opera
    - Correspondence and donation receipts, 1920s-1957 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Subseries F. Palestine Orchestra
    - Correspondence and programs, 1930s and 1940s, 1930s-1940s (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Subseries G. Palestine Philharmonic Orchestra
    - Letter, 1934; program, 1947; and Palestine Philharmonic Society membership solicitation pamphlet, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Subseries H. Purim
    - Items relating to Purim celebrations in Tel Aviv; including tickets, invitations, and two programs, 1920s-1940s. (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Miśḥaḳ Purim: yutsag bi-fetiḥat ha-ḥag be-Furim 693., 1933-03; 1.0 volume(s)
        Adloyada (Festival); Purim
    - Sign: Iriyat Tel-Aviv va’adat ha-adloyadah (Municipal Purim celebration committee), undated., Ṿa‘adat ha-‘Adloyada‘. (Flat-box 22, Folder 1)
    - Shire-Purim asher yafitsu otam ba-‘am be-yom 3, 14 Adar 2, 692: ‘al-yede Maḳhelat ha-Operah (ha-rishonah) ṿeha-maḳhelot shel ha-Mosad le-hafatsat musiḳah ba-‘am / ha-menatseaḥ, M. Rabinovits., 1932-03-22; 1.0 volume(s); Ṿa‘adah le-sidur ha-ḥagigot ṿeha-‘Adloyoda‘ be-Furim 692.
      Rabinovits, M; Adloyada (Festival); Festivals--Israel--Tel Aviv; Purim; Songs
    - Ḳerovets le-Furim, 715: ha-tokhnit ha-rishmit shel ‘Adloyada‘., 1955-03; 1.0 item(s); Ṿaʻadah le-ḥagigot Purim. (Tel Aviv, Israel)
      Adloyada (Festival); Festivals--Israel--Tel Aviv; Programs; Purim
    - Shire-Purim asher yafitsu otam ba-‘am be-yom 1, 14 Adar 2, 693: ‘l-yede ha-maḳhela ha-rishonah ha-Operah ha-E.Y. u-maḳhelot ‘amamiyot / ha-menatseaḥ, M. Rabinovits., 1933-03-12; 1.0 volume(s); Ṿa‘adah le-sidur ha-ḥagigot ṿeha-‘Adloyoda‘ be-Furim 692.
    - Purim 689., 1929; 1.0 item(s); Nafshe ha-masekhot ha-mesoratiyim shel B. Agadati.; Ḳaʼushinsḳi, Barukh, 1895-1976
      Festivals--Israel--Tel Aviv; Programs; Purim
    - Shire-Purim asher yafitsu otam ba-‘am be-yom 3, 14 Adar 2, 692: ‘l-yede Maḳhelat ha-Operah (ha-rishonah) ṿeha-maḳhelot shel ha-Mosad le-hafatsat musiḳah ba-‘am / ha-menatseaḥ, M. Rabinovits., 1932-03-22; 1.0 volume(s); Ṿa‘adah le-sidur ha-ḥagigot ṿeha-‘Adloyoda‘ be-Furim 692.
  - Subseries I. Sheet music
    - Ten items; including "Shir Tel-Aviv/Tel-Aviv song," music by S. Ferszko, words by R. Klachkin, Tel Aviv: Omanuth, no date, ca.1940s or 1950s. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Subseries J. Sports
    - "Maccabbi" memorabilia; mifal ha-payis (lottery) tickets; membership cards; correspondence, 1920s-1950s. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Program of events from the first Maccabiah, 1932 (Flat-box 22, Folder 1)
    - ha-Kenes ha-artsi ha-ḥamishi, Tel Aviv, Pesaḥ, 629 / Histadrut artsit le-hit‘amlut ule-sporṭ "Makabi" Erets-Yiśra’el., 1929-04; 1.0 item(s); Histadrut artsit le-hit‘amlut ule-sporṭ "Makabi" Erets-Yiśra’el. (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Programs; Sports--Palestine
  - Subseries K. Tel Aviv Museum
    - Correspondence; tickets; donation receipts, 1930s-1940s. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Subseries L. Writing, unpublished
    - Handmade booklet, "Jerusalemites see Tel-Aviv," by M. Azriel, no date; manuscript in Hebrew, "Hakdamah la-sefer shel Ilan Shamir: Petah davar: Tel-Aviv ke-medinah ba-derekh," Shelomoh Lahat (Mayor of Tel-Aviv-Yafo from 1974-1993); photocopy, no date. (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Series III. Maps
  - Subseries A. Tel Aviv-Yafo, published
    - Maps, 1920s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Maps, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Ha-Shekhunah ha-hadashah: Tel Aviv ha-morhevet ezor alef [The new neighborhood: Greater Tel Aviv area A]. Davar newspaper insert 3.12.33. (Map-folder 27)
      - Survey of Palestine: Jaffa Tel Aviv. 1935 (Map-folder 27)
    - Maps, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Maps, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Maps, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Maps, 1940-1948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Tel-Aviv Jaffa: New edition August 1942 (Map-folder 27)
    - Maps, 1940-1948 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Maps, 1940-1948 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Maps, 1940-1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Maps, after 1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Maps, after 1948 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Maps, after 1948 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Maps, after 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B. Tel Aviv-Yafo, unpublished
    - Maps, no date (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Maps, no date (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Maps, no date, "Key plan to the urban blocks of Tel Aviv" (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Maps, 1930s, 1940s, and no date (Map-folder 17)
    - Maps, 1930s, 1940s, and no date (Map-folder 18)
    - Maps, 1930s, 1940s, and no date (Map-folder 19)
    - Map of new road, 1926 (Map-folder 23)
  - Subseries C. Other areas
    - Map of Ramat Gan in honor of city's fiftieth anniversary [1971]; map of Israel, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Subseries D. Survey maps
    - Esh Sheikh Muwannis, maps of registration blocks 6623; 6624 [2]; 6627; 6628; 6629; 6631; 6632; 6635; 6637, 1933-1940 (Map-folder 25)
    - Salama, maps of registration blocks 6150; 6161; 6157; 6164, 1941-1942 (Map-folder 26)
    - Wilhelma, maps of registration blocks 17 & 18, 1932 (Map-folder 27)
- Series IV. Noncommercial institutions
  - Subseries A. Associations, committees, etc.
    - Documents relating to the Committee of the Jewish Community of Jaffa and Tel Aviv (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Documents relating to the Jewish National Fund (Keren kayemet) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Handbills and other documents relating to ethnic and religious organizations, including the Yemen Community in Palestine (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Documents and other materials relating to maritime associations, 1930s (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Documents relating to various noncommercial institutions, including the Jewish Agency for Palestine and the Women’s International Zionist Organisation (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Documents relating to various noncommercial institutions, including the Jewish Agency for Palestine and the Women’s International Zionist Organisation (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Documents relating to various noncommercial institutions, including the Jewish Agency for Palestine and the Women’s International Zionist Organisation (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Round wood and rubber ink-stamp, Vaad toshve shekhunat Montifyori Tel Aviv (Montefiore neighborhood residents’ committee), no date (Flat-box 18)
    - Documents relating to various noncommercial institutions, including the Zevulun maritime association (Flat-box 22, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B. Charities
    - Documents, including lottery tickets, relating to charitable institutions (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Documents, including lottery tickets, relating to charitable institutions (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Subseries C. Other cities
    - Documents relating to Jaffa, including building permits in Ottoman Turkish from the 1920s (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Documents relating to Ramat Gan (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Subseries D. Education
    - Municipal file containing correspondence, data, and blueprints for construction of schools in Tel Aviv, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Documents relating to schools in Tel Aviv (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Documents relating to schools in Tel Aviv (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Matriculation certificate of Rivkah Tsiran, 1937, and two class pictures, ca. 1927 and 1936 (Flat-box 23)
  - Subseries E. Electric Company (Hevrat ha-hashmal)
    - Documents relating to the Electric Company (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Subseries F. Government of Palestine and government of Israel